# Stanislav Starishko

**Software Engineer** 

Glasgow, G72 8PG, UK | WhatsApp/Tel: 07387914778 | Email: starishko.s@gmail.com

Web: https://github.com/StanStarishko/Portfolio | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/starishko/

Permit: Category B | Legally authorized to work in the UK

# **Summary:**

Motivated results-driven professional with years of experience, recognised for assessing operational needs, and developing solutions to save costs, improve revenues and drive customer satisfaction. Resourceful, well-organised with excellent leadership and team-building record. Passionate Developer with experience in data accuracy, management. Independent problem-solver focused on customer service, product development. Works well under tight deadlines.

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Programming Languages: 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce), T-SQL, R, Java (Collections, Lambda Expressions), Python (Flask, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Lambda Expressions), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++
- Development Tools & Environments: Delivering complex (ERP) enterprise level systems, Writing secure and high-quality code, Full Life Cycle and Decisions Architecture, Object-Oriented (OOP), Modular Programming, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), MVC, SOLID, QA MT/AT, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development (TDD), BDD, Design of architecture IT products, services and solutions, AWS, Lambda, S3, APIs, Jira, Trello, Data and system analyst
- Databases: MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, and Time, Team, Product, Project, and Crisis Management

## **Key Skills:**

- Enthusiastic up for challenge
- Analytical and Outside The Box Thinking
   Crisis Resolution
- **Excellent Team Collaboration**
- Passionate about software
- Attention to Detail
- Team Productivity Enhancement
- Business Process Understanding
- Process Modernization

### **Education and Courses:**

PDA Programming for Data	SCQF8	Code Division	UK	07/2024 - 08/2024
PDA Cyber Resilience	SCQF8	Code Division, futureCoders	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
Cyber Engineers	CyberOps Associate	Cisco Networking Academy	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
PDA Software Development	SCQF7	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	08/2023 - 11/2023
NPA Software Development	SCQF6	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	04/2023 - 07/2023
NQ Access to Business Administration, Accounting and IT	SCQF4	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	01/2023 - 06/2023
Python	Fundamental	DataCamp	USA	11/2022 - 03/2023
New strategic thinking. Selection Management	Advanced	EVA Academy, Arkadiy Tsuker	Ukraine	05/2019 - 05/2019
Project Management by Agile, Scrum and Kanban	Advanced	EVA Academy	Ukraine	11/2018 - 04/2019
Corporate course of business changes and transformation	МВА	Institute of Adizes, Ukrainian Office	USA	02/2018 - 09/2018
Programming for Computing Devices and Automated Systems	BTEC, SCQF7	Automation and Telemechan College	Ukraine	09/1990 - 03/1993

#### **Achievements:**

- Enforced innovative timekeeping facial recognition in ERP rise 80% HR processes within just 2.5 months
- Developed strategy plan to enhance support software for 900+ retail outlets and 3500+ users, achieving business efficiency improvement 10%
- Implemented seamless execution comprehensive automation plan for manufacturing within ambitious 10-month timeline
- Solved problems in 280 1C databases on MSSQL, reduced update time by 98%, from 2.5 months to 3-5 days

- Significantly reduced exchange time by 99.5% from 8-14 hours to 2-5 minutes by implemented high-speed data synchronization for 1C (similar to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce)
- Exhibited phenomenal efficiency surpassing projected 8-months milestones within just 2 weeks

## **Work History:**

Glasgow Film Theatre 08/2023 - Current

#### **Volunteer-Customer Assistant**

Glasgow, UK

- Oversaw daily operations involving more than **50 customer** interactions, ticket validation, and post-performance cleanup for optimal customer experience
- Provided exceptional customer service, promptly addressing queries and offering product recommendations to enhance shopping experience

EVOS 09/2021 – 02/2022

#### **Director of Digital Transformation**

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Business Areas: Good Food, Manufacture

- Established ERP systems increased accounting and finance productivity by 30%
- Implemented measures to stop the growth of technological debt in just two months

Freelance 11/2019 – 08/2021

Software Engineer Dnipro, Ukraine

Business Areas: Retail, Logistic, Warehouse

- Developed 1C software modules to improve financial reporting speed to 25%
- Enhanced software components by troubleshooting and modifying code

EVA 10/2018 – 11/2019

# **Head Software Department**

10/2018 – 11/2019 Dnipro, Ukraine

Business Areas: Retail

- Incorporated cutting-edge techniques like SBS feedback, hybrid Agile, Scrum, CorpScrum ,Prince2, Waterfall approach leading to a notable 20% boost in team efficiency
- Effectively managed 10+ projects, each lasting 1-3 years, played pivotal role in creation payment calendar
- Executed 20+ short-term projects, each lasting up to 6 months, consistently meeting all deadlines
- Successfully roll out sophisticated ERP caused impressive 10% rise accounting finance department productivity
- Implemented strategy effectively halted company's technological debt growth within just 4 months

Corporation Alef 03/2014 – 10/2018

## Re-entry from Junior 1C8 Developer to Head of Software Department

Dnipro, Ukraine

Business Areas: Real Estate, Metallurgy, Alcohol, Dental Implants, Manufacture

• Achieved impressive 80% enhancement support efficiency establishment by transformation initiative

Company Adeon 02/2007 – 03/2014
Co-owner/CEO Dnipro, Ukraine

Business Areas: Franchising 1C, IT Consulting and Favours

• Delivered 12+ long-term projects, each completed under budget within specified timelines of 8 to 18 months by **1C** technology (akin to **Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce**)

#### **Retail and Logistic Companies**

10/1991 - 02/2007

Software Developer

Dnipro, Ukraine

Business Areas: Retail, Logistic, Warehouse, Pharmacies

- In 2003, rapid effectively, for one month, retrained to 1C developer (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce)
- Established proficiency in Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++, showcasing decade software development excellence from 1991-2003

**Languages:** English - Intermediate, Ukrainian – Native, Russian - Native

Hobbies & Interests: Traveling, exploring new technologies, personal development